Now we're going to cover the ITTOs of
Perform Integrated Change Control,
one of the most important processes.
So I have mentioned it before,
but now we're going to cover it in depth.
Once we are baselines, we're done planning,
going through our planning processes.
We at least have our initial reference for
scope, time, and cost.
All change requests must go to this
process.
So 113, in your PINBOC.
And you'll see on the first couple of
lines, this is where we're reviewing all
change requests, approving changes,
and managing changes to deliverables,
documents, the plan, and communicating the
decisions.
So it's really important.
So let's, this is another thing that we
have above the ITTOs.
One of our jobs is to prevent unnecessary
changes.
Changes shouldn't just happen Willy-nilly
on our projects.
We have a formal change control system.
So that's really important.
I also want to remind you that you are
usually authorized to approve corrective
and preventive actions if a baseline isn't
affected.
Sponsors needed if change requests will
affect the baselines especially the cost
baseline and then assume for the exam that
you have a CCB change control board a
formal chartered group like a steering
committee who will review evaluate approve
reject or delay all change requests so
let's look at the ITTOs our inputs the
project management plan big the change
management plan says how changes will be
made on our project and keep in mind any
stakeholder involved in the project can
submit a change request so we have to
immediately have that change management
plan we also created as we developed the
project management plan change and
configuration management the details that
we need to document and oh Always make
sure we're working from the latest
versions, plans, baselines.
Of course, our baselines are included in
our plan.
Project documents, we
will have the requirements
and requirements traceability matrix.
It links every requirement to a
deliverable.
All right, big here will be the work
performance report.
To know whether or not a
change request should be
approved, we need to know
what's happening with every.
aspect of the project.
So remember the work
performance report comes
from us in monitor and
control the project work.
This again is the only way that we raise
awareness can take action and make
decisions based on the
reports knowing what's
happening with every
aspect of the project.
The change requests themselves come in
here of course.
And then you have those EEFs and OPAs.
You can run but you can't hide,
they impact you.
So we sees them throughout integration and
all our planning processes.
So tools and techniques will use expert
judgment, change control tools,
data analysis.
So we and our team will do an impact
assessment.
This is big.
An impact assessment part of the meeting
that we're having.
We'll do an impact assessment for every
single change request.
how will it impact the rest of our project
the scope quality schedule costs resources
we need and then we'll do a cost benefit
analysis our alternatives shouldn't cost
more than it will benefit all right so
we'll always do a cost benefit analysis
we'll make decisions so we'll vote so you
have unanimity where everybody agrees we
get consensus Well, that's often hard to
get.
So a way we can get unanimity is anonymity
called Delphi.
We're going to keep everything anonymous.
We'll see that again when we collect
requirements.
All right, so we'll do voting or one
person makes the decisions.
So it's called autocratic decision making,
aka it used to be called dictatorship.
One person makes the decisions.
So we usually try to stay away from that
if we can.
Multi-cryteria decision analysis means we
have a lot of criteria.
We've got to try to rank prioritize.
And of course, we're having a meeting.
So your output, I'm going right here
first.
This is where we create our change log,
perform integrated change control.
The output is the change.
change log.
So it will list every change request and
then the disposition right now,
whether it's being approved, rejected,
or delayed, deferred.
Because sometimes we hold off.
Let's wait and see what happens.
Then we'll review it again.
All right.
So this is where we create the change log.
We will communicate the
decisions made here, whether
the change request is
approved, rejected, or delayed.
All that is in the change log.
What else will come out?
Approved change requests.
They will go into which process.
You may remember direct and manage the
project work to be implemented.
All right.
But before those approved change requests
go out to be implemented, all approved
change requests will lead to plan and
document.
updates we will update any plan strategies
approaches or baselines if they are
impacted as well as documents requirements
resources costs schedule whatever the case
is okay so just know
that's always a trio change
requests if approved lead to
plan and document updates